## KISHORE VASAN

## Boston, United States

github.com/kishorevasan ♦ vasan.k@northeastern.edu ♦ kishorevasan.github.io

#### OBJECTIVE STATEMENT

A highly motivated and spirited learner who is excited about what life offers. My research builds and utilizes tools from network science, machine learning, and data visualization to build social processes in clinical sciences/drug discovery and web3 platforms.

## **EDUCATION**

Northeastern University

September 2020 - Present

PhD in Network Science

Boston, Massachussets

Research direction: human behavior in the metaverse

University of Washington

Advisor: Albert-Laszlo Barabasi

September 2016 - June 2020

Bachelor of Science

Major: Informatics - Data Science; Minor: Quantitative Science

Advisor: Jevin West

Seattle, Washington

## TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Computer Languages

Python, R, mySQL, d3.JS, Three.JS, Java, React, HTML

Software & Tools

RStudio, Gephi, Cytoscape, networkx, matplotlib, pandas, pytorch

#### EXPERIENCE

Center for Complex Networks Research, Network Science Institute

Sept 2020 - Present

Graduate Research Associate

#### Social and economic connectedness in the metaverse

May 2022 - Present

- · Exploration of physical land is heavily constrained by commute times, affecting the social circles and friendships. The emergence of a metaverse removes such constrains allowing for new forms of interactions.
- · Through this project I seek to understand the patterns of exploration in the metaverse and the social mobility of users within it.

## Drug target innovation in clinical trials

September 2020 - Present

- · Novel drug in clinical trials experience a low success rate, so we ask, what are the social patterns governing the collective exploration of novel targets?
- · The goal of the project is to understand why pharmaceutical companies choose certain protein targets over others for new drugs and formulate strategies that could improve equitable clinical trial exploration.

## Discerning artist success in NFTs and Crypto Art

April 2021 - December 2021

- · NFTs took the world by storm after Beeple sold his famous artwork for over \$69 Million. But are all artists equally successful? What is the role of collectors, and fan base in ensuring artist success?
- · We identify the important variables that determine success of new artists, demonstrate the presence of taste in the collecting behavior of collectors, and measure the network effects in crypto art.

-----

## DataLab, Information School

September 2017 - August 2020

Undergraduate Research Associate

## Collective dynamics in co-funding of clinical trials

July 2019 - August 2020

- · Assessing the scientific impact of different funding strategies in clinical trials. The goal is to untangle the relationship between funding agencies through a co-funding network.
- · Funded by the Bill & Melinda Gates Foundation and Mary Gates Research Scholarship.

## Measuring scientific buzz using keywords

July 2018 - June 2019

- · Compaing the applicability of keywords and abstracts in describing research trends. I discovered that keywords are a powerful resource for identifying hot topics than abstracts.
- · Funded through Mary Gates Research Scholarship.

## Mapping cross-departmental collaboration at UW

September 2017 - August 2018

- · How impactful are multi-departmental collaboration at a large scale public university? We discovered an effect of compartmentalization where departments that collaborate together, also cite each other.
- · I worked on disambiguation of departmental and institutional affiliations of authors over 60k papers

-----

## Information School, University of Washington

Spring 2018 - Spring 2019

Teaching Assistant, INFO 201 - Data Visualization using R.

· As a TA for over 100 students, I conducted weekly lab sessions, answered online questions, and graded weekly assignments. The course covers source control and interactive data visualization principles.

-----

## Genpact Inc.

June 2017 - August 2017

Data Science Intern

- · Enhancing customer care analytics by automatic emotion recognition system by extracting voice features and unsupervised topic clustering of GM Financial chat transcripts using latent semantic analysis.
- · Worked in a team of 4 people and presented a proof of concept to the upper management.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### Journal Publications

## Quantifying NFT-driven networks in crypto art

Feb 2022

Kishore Vasan, Milan Janosov, and Albert-Laszlo Barabasi.

Scientific Reports

The hidden influence of communities in collaborative funding of clinical science Aug 2021 Kishore Vasan and Jevin West.

Royal Society Open Science

## Network effects in unbiased drug-target exploration in clinical trials

TBA

Kishore Vasan, Deisy Gysi, and Albert-Laszlo Barabasi.

In Prep, Target journal: Nature Medicine

## Conference Papers

# SciSight: Combining faceted navigation and research group detection for COVID-19 exploratory scientific search May 2020

Tom Hope, Jason Portenoy\*, Kishore Vasan\*, Jonathan Borchardt\*, Eric Horvitz, Daniel Weld, Marti Hearst, and Jevin West.

Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) 2020 systems track. Online.

## Is together better? Examining scientific collaboration across multiple authors, departments and institutions. August 2018

Lovenoor Aulck, Kishore Vasan and Jevin West.

Knowledge Discovery and Data mining(KDD): BigScholar workshop 2018. London, UK.

## Measuring scientific buzz.

March 2019

Kishore Vasan and Jevin West.

Information Schools Conference (iConference) 2019 as a poster. Washington, DC.

## MEDIA COVERAGE

**Artnet News.** Want to Succeed as an NFT Artist? Here Are 5 Things to Know, According to a New Study of One of the Biggest Crypto-Art Platforms.

March 2022

Nature News. Artificial-intelligence tools aim to tame the coronavirus literature.

June 2020

Science. Scientists are drowning in COVID-19 papers. Can new tools keep them affoat? May 2020

## **PRESENTATIONS**

Whats the story with NFTs? Cambridge Arts Association panel.

May 2022

Research Exposed! Population Health Initiative (PHI) panel

March 2020

Undergraduate Research Symposium Presented work on collaborative funding

May 2020

#### SERVICE AND ACHIEVEMENTS

## Reviewer

- · Book, Oxford University Press
- · Journal article, Electronic Markets

## Mary Gates Research Scholarship

2018 - 2019

- · A highly selective award given to undergraduates at the University of Washington pursuing research.
- · I received this award to develop techniques to map research trends and study funding mechanisms.

## Society of Network Scientists, UW

Fall 2019 - Summer 2020

Co-Founder, Vice President

- · A campus wide initiative with an aim to promote and encourage research in network science. The organization acts as a platform for fellow researchers to interact and collaborate.
- · We host weekly reading groups on social networks, panel discussions, and invite distinguished speakers.
- · The group also serves an eScience Special Interest Group (SIG) on networks, and a local chapter of *The Society of Young Network Scientists* (SYNS).

<sup>\* -</sup> denotes equal contribution

- · Helped review undergraduate applicants for Informatics, a competitive major.
- · Comprehensively reviewed the applicant based on personal statement, intent to major, and grades.

## **CLASSROOM PROJECTS**

#### In search of food

September - December 2020

The breakdown and robustness of food flow in the United States Complex Networks and applications

- · Food flow patterns are an essential component of society and serves as a complex system of distribution between producers, consumers, and distributors. Yet, we know little about the impact of food epidemics.
- · I find that every county is highly dependent on counties for specific food commodity, indicating a complex web of connections driven by food commodity.
- · Finally, I find that the network is fairly robust towards targeted removal of distribution channels primarily due to the local dependence for food supplies.

## Crawling Wikipedia Graph

April 2019 - June 2019

Exploring the edit dynamics of users in Wikipedia

Statistical Analysis of Social Networks

- · Mining large graphs reveals information; temporal network of the same reveal evolution. However, performing novel algorithms on these large graphs can be computationally expensive. We need methods that can provide an un-biased sample that would be representative of the underlying large network.
- · In this work, we evaluated different random walks by crawling a large online editing network, Wikipedia.
- · Our *findings* include simple random walk is ineffective when sampling graphs with high tailed distribution, and re-weighted random walk outperforms other methods for graph sampling.

## COURSEWORK

## Northeastern University

PHYS 5116 - Complex networks and application I

**NETS 6116** - Complex networks and application II

PHYS 7332 - Graph machine learning

POLS 7334 - Social network analysis

**NETS 7341** - Network economics

PHYS 7335 - Dynamical processes in complex networks

**BIOT 5120** - Foundations in Biotechnology

## University of Washington

 ${\bf QSCI~403}$  - Introduction to resampling inference

QSCI 482 - Statistical inference in applied research I

QSCI 483 - Statistical inference in applied research II

QSCI 497 - Complex analysis using agent based models

STAT 567 - Statistical analysis of social networks

MATH 308 - Matrix algebra with applications

MATH 309 - Linear analysis

 ${\bf MATH~324}$  - Advanced multi-variable calculus I

 ${\bf INFO~371}$  - Advanced methods in data science

 ${\bf INFO~430}$  - Advanced database design and management

 $\mathbf{CSE}\ \mathbf{373}$  - Data structures and algorithms

 $\mathbf{CSE}\ \mathbf{415}$  - Introduction to artificial intelligence